Guide to the John R. Mott Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Biographical Documentation, 1881-1885; Series VII
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. universities, 1890 (Box 150, Folder 2501)
  - Marriage to Leila White, 1891 (Box 150, Folder 2502)
  - YMCA Convention in Nebraska, 1892 (Box 150, Folder 2503)
  - YMCA International Conference, 1894 (Box 150)
  - World trip- Europe, Near East, 1895 (Box 150, Folder 2504)
  - World trip-Ceylon, India, 1895-1896 (Box 150, Folder 2505)
  - World trip-Australia, New Zealand, 1896 (Box 150, Folder 2506)
  - World trip-Japan, misc., 1896-1897 (Box 150, Folder 2507)
  - Conferences, visits-Oxford, Cambridge, 1898 (Box 150, Folder 2508)
  - Conferences, visits-including Univ. of Pa., Edinburgh Univ., 1899 (Box 150, Folder 2509)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. universities, 1900-1901 (Box 151, Folder 2510)
  - World trip-Japan, 1901 (Box 151, Folder 2511)
  - World trip-China, 1901 (Box 151, Folder 2512)
  - World trip-Ceylon, India, 1901 (Box 151, Folder 2513)
  - WSCF Convention, Soro, 1902 (Box 151)
  - SVM Convention, Toronto, 1902 (Box 151)
  - Conferences, visits-Australia, New Zealand, 1903 (Box 151, Folder 2514)
  - Conferences, visits-Italy, 1904 (Box 151, Folder 2515)
  - Conferences, visits-misc. universi-ties, 1903-1905 (Box 151, Folder 2516)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, China banquet, 1906 (Box 151, Folder 2517)
  - Conferences, visits-South Africa, 1906 (Box 151, Folder 2518)
  - Conferences, visits-South America, 1906 (Box 151, Folder 2519)
  - Conferences, visits-Far East, 1907 (Box 151, Folder 2520)
  - Conferences, visits to universities; British Bible Society membership, 1907-1908 (Box 151, Folder 2521)
  - Conferences, visits-Great Britain, 1908 (Box 151, Folder 2522)
  - Conferences, visits-Russia, 1909 (Box 151, Folder 2523)
  - Conferences, visits-Italy, 1909 (Box 151, Folder 2524)
  - Conferences, visits-Hungary, Germany Offered General Secretaryship of Fed- 1909 oral Council of Churches (Box 152, Folder 2525)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S., Canadian universities, 1910 (Box 152, Folder 2526)
  - YMCA Convention, Toronto, 1910 (Box 152)
  - Honorary LL.D-Edinburgh Audience with British Royalty, 1910 (Box 152, Folder 2527)
  - Honorary LL.D-Princeton, 1911 (Box 152, Folder 2528)
  - Conferences, visits-Swiss universities, 1911 (Box 152, Folder 2529)
  - Conferences, visits-Greece, Near East, Servia, England, Ireland, 1911, 1912 (Box 152, Folder 2530)
  - Power of attorney to LWM, 1912 (Box 152, Folder 2531)
  - World trip-India, 1912-1913 (Box 152, Folder 2532)
  - World trip-China, 1913 (Box 152, Folder 2533)
  - World trip-General, 1912-1913 (Box 152, Folder 2534)
  - World trip-Korea, Japan, 1913 (Box 152, Folder 2535)
  - Ambassador to China position declined, 1913 (Box 152, Folder 2536)
  - Decision to devote more time to Continuation Committee, 1913 (Box 152, Folder 2537)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, 1913 (Box 152, Folder 2538)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. universi- ties and conventions, 1914 (Box 152, Folder 2539)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, 1914 (Box 152, Folder 2540)
  - Conferences, visits-Postville, IA, 1914, 1915, 1917 (Box 152, Folder 2541)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. and Canadian universities, 1915 (Box 152, Folder 2542)
  - Appointed General Secretary YMCA, 1915 (Box 152, Folder 2543)
  - 50th birthday-telegrams, 1915 (Box 153, Folder 2544)
  - American and Mexican Joint Commission, 1916 (Box 153, Folder 2545)
  - American and Mexican Joint Commission, 1916 (Box 153, Folder 2546)
  - American and Mexican Joint Commission, 1916 (Box 153, Folder 2547)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. universities, 1916 (Box 153, Folder 2548)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, 1916 (Box 153)
  - Criticisms of Mott's actions during WWI by Germans, 1916-1920 (Box 153, Folder 2549)
  - Special Diplomatic Mission to Russia-Official papers, 1917 (Box 153, Folder 2550)
  - Special Diplomatic Mission to Russia-clippings, memorabilia, 1917 (Box 153, Folder 2551)
  - Special Diplomatic Mission to Russia-Mott's activities, 1917 (Box 153, Folder 2552)
  - Conferences, visits-U.S. colleges, 1917 (Box 153, Folder 2553)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, 1918 (Box 153, Folder 2554)
  - Honors: Distinguished Service Medal (USA); French Legion of Honor; Order of the Crown of Siam; Portugese Order of Christ; Cornell Semi-centennial Celebration (1919) (Box 153, Folder 2555)
  - Honors: Order of the Crown of Italy; Third Class of the Imperial Order of the Meiji; YMCA War Work Council; Resolution of SVM, 1920 (Box 153, Folder 2556)
  - Conferences, visits-Europe, 1920 (Box 153, Folder 2557)
  - Conferences, visits-China, Japan, 1922 (Box 153, Folder 2558)
  - Lac des Iles Regatta, 1922 (Box 154, Folder 2559)
  - Honors: Hungarian Red Cross, 1923 (Box 154, Folder 2560)
  - Conferences, visits-England, 1923 (Box 154, Folder 2561)
  - Religious Work Emphasis tour, 1923 (Box 154, Folder 2562)
  - Conference of Christian Workers- Constantine, Algeria, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2563)
  - Conference of Christian Workers- Helwan, Egypt, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2564)
  - Regional Conference for Syria and Palestine-Brummana, Syria, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2565)
  - General Conference of Workers Among Moslems-Jerusalem, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2566)
  - Conferences, visits-Greece, Turkey, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2567)
  - Conferences, visits-Serbia, Bulgaria, Roumania, Czechoslovakia, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2568)
  - Conferences, visits-Poland, Germany, 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2569)
  - Honors: Greek Order of the Savior Order of Polonia Restituta (Poland), 1924 (Box 154, Folder 2570)
  - Visits to towns in U.S., 1925 (Box 154, Folder 2571)
  - 60th Birthday, 1925 (Box 154, Folder 2572)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-General, 1925-1926 (Box 154, Folder 2573)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Japan, 1925 (Box 155, Folder 2574)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Korea, 1925 (Box 155, Folder 2575)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-China, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2576)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-China, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2577)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Philippines, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2578)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2579)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2580)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2581)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2582)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 155, Folder 2583)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Netherlands Indies, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2584)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Australia, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2585)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Australia, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2586)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Australia, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2587)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Australia, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2588)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-Australia, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2589)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-New Zealand, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2590)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-New Zealand, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2591)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-New Zealand, 1926 (Box 156, Folder 2592)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-New Zealand, 1926 (Box 157, Folder 2593)
  - Pacific Basin Tour-New Zealand, 1926 (Box 157, Folder 2594)
  - World Conference YMCA, Helsingfors Mott appointed Chairman of World's Alliance, 1926 (Box 157, Folder 2595)
  - Miscellaneous incl. Rattvik, Sweden, 1926 (Box 157, Folder 2596)
  - Itinerary Feb.-May, 1927 (Box 157, Folder 2597)
  - Conferences, visits-Holland, Paris, Germany, 1927 (Box 157, Folder 2598)
  - Conferences, visits-Poland, Hungary, 1927 (Box 157, Folder 2599)
  - Conferences, visits-Canada, 1927 (Box 157, Folder 2600)
  - Physical examination, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2601)
  - Methodist convention, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2601)
  - Endorsement of Hoover, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2601)
  - Conferences, visits-Sofia Conferences with Orthodox Church leaders, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2602)
  - IMC Jerusalem meeting, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2603)
  - Resignation from General Secretaryship of YMCA, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2604)
  - Resignation from General Secretaryship of YMCA, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2605)
  - Resolution of Committee of Reference and Council, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2606)
  - WSCF Conference-Mysore, 1928 (Box 157, Folder 2607)
  - World trip-Bangkok Conference, 1929 (Box 157, Folder 2608)
  - World trip-Philippines, 1929 Mar (Box 158, Folder 2609)
  - World trip-Japan, 1929 Apr (Box 158, Folder 2610)
  - World trip-Korea, 1929 Apr (Box 158, Folder 2611)
  - World trip-China, 1929 Apr-May (Box 158, Folder 2612)
  - World trip-General, 1929 (Box 158, Folder 2613)
  - Honors: Order of the First Class of the Sacred Treasure (Japan), 1929 May (Box 158, Folder 2614)
  - Itinerary, 1930 Feb-Jun (Box 158, Folder 2615)
  - Meeting in Philadelphia, 1930 Jan (Box 158, Folder 2615)
  - Consultation of Leaders of Orthodox Churches with Leaders of YMCA, Athens, 1930 Feb 25-28 (Box 158, Folder 2616)
  - Consultation regarding the Orthodox Churches and Missionary Work Among the Moslems, Athens, 1930 Feb 28-Mar 1 (Box 158, Folder 2617)
  - Conferences, visits-Germany, 1930 Feb (Box 158, Folder 2618)
  - Denmark, 1930 Mar (Box 158, Folder 2618)
  - Conferences, visits-Sweden, Norway, 1930 Mar (Box 158, Folder 2619)
  - Conferences, visits-Great Britain, 1930 Mar-May (Box 158, Folder 2620)
  - Honorary membership in "Pro Fide et Christianismot' (Sweden), 1930 (Box 158, Folder 2621)
  - Honor: Order of the White Lion (Czechoslovakia), 1930 (Box 158, Folder 2622)
  - Walker Trust Lectures on Leadership, University of St. Andrews, 1931 Feb (Box 158, Folder 2623)
  - Honorary LL.D.-Brown University, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2624)
  - Commencement address-Upper towa Univ., 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2624)
  - Interview, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2624)
  - Bangor Theological Seminary Convocation, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2625)
  - Tuskegee Institute visit, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2625)
  - Prohibition views, 1931 (Box 158, Folder 2625)
  - Conferences, visits-Athens, Greece, 1933 Apr (Box 158, Folder 2626)
  - Conferences, visits-Belgrade, Yugoslavia, 1933 May (Box 158, Folder 2627)
  - Conferences, visits-Sofia, Bulgaria, 1933 May (Box 158, Folder 2628)
  - Conferences, visits-Bucharest, Roumania, 1933 May (Box 159, Folder 2629)
  - Conferences with Russian Student Christian Movement, France, 1933 May, Jun (Box 159, Folder 2630)
  - Itinerary, Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box 159, Folder 2631)
  - Conferences, visits-Africa, 1934 (Box 159, Folder 2632)
  - Conferences, visits-Africa, 1934 (Box 159, Folder 2633)
  - Conferences, visits-Japan, 1935,Mar, Apr (Box 159, Folder 2634)
  - Conferences, visits-Korea, 1935 Apr (Box 159, Folder 2635)
  - Conferences, visits-Shanghai, China, 1935 Apr (Box 159, Folder 2636)
  - Conferences, visits-Nanking, China, 1935 Apr (Box 159, Folder 2637)
  - Conferences, visits-Peiping, China, 1935 Apr (Box 159, Folder 2638)
  - Conferences, visits-Hankow, China, 1935 Apr (Box 159, Folder 2639)
  - Conferences, visits-Philippines, 1935 May (Box 159, Folder 2640)
  - 70th birthday, 1935 May (Box 159, Folder 2641)
  - Itinerary, 1935 Dec (Box 160, Folder 2642)
  - SVM Convention, 1935 Dec (Box 160, Folder 2642)
  - Itinerary, 1936 Jan (Box 160, Folder 2643)
  - Visit to Berlin, 1936 Jun (Box 160, Folder 2643)
  - Conversations with Gandhi, 1936 Dec (Box 160, Folder 2643)
  - Honorary membership-The Bible Foundation-, 1937 (Box 160, Folder 2644)
  - Honorary Canon-Washington Cathedral, 1937 (Box 160, Folder 2644)
  - Conferences/visits-India, 1937 Feb (Box 160, Folder 2645)
  - Conferences/visits-Near East, 1937 Feb-Mar (Box 160, Folder 2646)
  - Itinerary, 1937 Sep-Dec (Box 160, Folder 2647)
  - Conferences/visits-Great Britain, 1937 (Box 160, Folder 2648)
  - Conferences/visits-Europe, 1938 (Box 160, Folder 2649)
  - Illustrated greeting from Prague YMCA (OVERSIZE), 1938 (Box OV1)
  - Membership in Athenaeum Club, London, 1938 Apr (Box 160, Folder 2650)
  - Estonian Red Cross, 1938 May (Box 160, Folder 2650)
  - Cornell 50th Reunion, 1938 Jun (Box 160, Folder 2650)
  - IMC Conference-India, 1938 Dec (Box 160, Folder 2651)
  - Conversation with Gandhi, 1938 Dec (Box 160, Folder 2651)
  - Purchase of Orlando home, 1938 Mar (Box 160, Folder 2652)
  - Itinerary, 1938-1939 (Box 160, Folder 2652)
  - Award of the Silver Buffalo, Boy Scouts of America, 1939 Jun (Box 160, Folder 2653)
  - Award in Toronto, 1939 Oct (Box 160, Folder 2653)
  - Methodist uniting conference, 1939 Aug (Box 160, Folder 2654)
  - Itinerary, 1939-1940 (Box 160, Folder 2654)
  - Proposed visit to Russia, 1940? (Box 160, Folder 2655)
  - Visits in U.S., 1940 (Box 160, Folder 2655)
  - Conferences/visits-Mexico, 1940 Jan (Box 160, Folder 2656)
  - Conferences/visits-Puerto Rico, Santo Domingo, 1940 Mar (Box 160, Folder 2657)
  - Conferences/visits-Cuba, 1940 Apr (Box 160, Folder 2658)
  - Conferences/visits-Argentina, 1940 Jun (Box 160, Folder 2659)
  - Conferences/visits-Brazil, 1940 Jun (Box 160, Folder 2660)
  - Conferences/visits-South America, 1940 (Box 161, Folder 2661)
  - Miscellany, 1940-1941 (Box 161, Folder 2662)
  - Canadian School of Missions lectures, 1941 Mar (Box 161, Folder 2663)
  - Conferences/visits-Canal Zone, 1941 Apr (Box 161, Folder 2664)
  - Conferences/visits-Colombia, 1941 Apr (Box 161, Folder 2665)
  - Conferences/visits-Santiago, Chile, 1941 Apr (Box 161, Folder 2666)
  - Conferences/visits-Temuce, Chile, 1941 Apr (Box 161, Folder 2667)
  - Conference on Indian Work-Antofagasta, Chile, 1941 May (Box 161, Folder 2668)
  - Conferences/visits-Ecuador, 1941 May (Box 161, Folder 2669)
  - Conferences/visits-Guatemala, 1941 May (Box 161, Folder 2670)
  - Conferences/visits-Peru, 1941 May (Box 161, Folder 2671)
  - Conferences/visits-Canada, 1941 Sep-Nov (Box 161, Folder 2672)
  - Marker for Birthplace of JRM, 1941 (Box 161, Folder 2673)
  - Resignation from Chairmanship of International Missionary Council, 1942 Jan (Box 161, Folder 2674)
  - Honorary Chairman-Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1942 Jan (Box 161, Folder 2654)
  - Conferences/visits-Canada and U.S., 1942 (Box 161, Folder 2675)
  - Conferences/visits-U.S., 1943 (Box 161, Folder 2676)
  - Rollins Animated Magazine, 1943-1948 (Box 161, Folder 2676)
  - Honorary D. Litt.-Upper Iowa Univ., 1943 May (Box 161, Folder 2676)
  - Itineraries, miscellany, 1944-1945 (Box 161, Folder 2677)
  - Honorary LL.D. University of Toronto, 1944 Nov (Box 161, Folder 2677)
  - 80th birthday, 1945 May (Box 161, Folder 2678)
  - Miscellany, 1945, 1946 (Box 161, Folder 2679)
  - Conferences/visits-Europe, 1945 Jan-Apr (Box 161, Folder 2680)
  - Luncheon at Methodist Church, Orlando, 1946 Apr (Box 161, Folder 2681)
  - Prince Carl Medal (Sweden), 1946 May (Box 161, Folder 2681)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-announcements, events, 1946 Nov-Dec (Box 162, Folder 2682)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-announcements, events, 1946 Nov-Dec (Box 162, Folder 2683)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-compilation of messages to JRM, 1946 Dec (Box 162, Folder 2684)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-U.S. newspaper and magazine clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 162, Folder 2685)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-non-U.S. news- paper clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 162, Folder 2686)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-dinner in honor Of JRM, 1946 Dec (Box 162, Folder 2687)
  - Nobel Peace Prize-Cornell dinner, 1947 Feb (Box 162, Folder 2688)
  - Conferences/visits,Germany, 1947 Jun (Box 162, Folder 2689)
  - Niche statue-Trinity Methodist Church, Springfield, MA, 1947 Nov (Box 162, Folder 2690)
  - Miscellany, 1947 (Box 162, Folder 2691)
  - Conference of Heads of Autocephalous Churches, Moscow (Correction: Mott did not attend this conference), 1948 Jul (Box 162, Folder 2692)
  - Zion's Herald Award for Methodist Churchmanship World Council of Churches-Amsterdam 1948 Miscellany 1948, 1948 Dec (Box 163, Folder 2693)
  - Conferences/visits-Far East, 1949 Mar-Apr (Box 163, Folder 2694)
  - Miscellany, 1949-1951 (Box 163, Folder 2695)
  - YMCA Citation, 1951 Jun (Box 163, Folder 2696)
  - Conferences/visits-Turkey, 1951 Aug (Box 163, Folder 2697)
  - SVM Conference, 1951 Dec (Box 163, Folder 2698)
  - Itinerary Marriage to Agnes Peter 1953 Jul, 1953 Jun (Box 163, Folder 2699)
  - Commander's Cross of the Order of Merit (Federated Republic of Germany), 1953 Dec (Box 163, Folder 2700)
  - 89th Birthday, 1954 May (Box 163, Folder 2701)
  - Death of JRM, 1955 Jan 31 (Box 163, Folder 2702)
  - Disposition of Mott papers and library, 1955 (Box 163, Folder 2702a)
  - JRM Fellowship Fund, 1956 (Box 163, Folder 2703)
  - JRM Memorial Tablet-Washington Cathedral, 1958 Jun (Box 163, Folder 2703)
  - World Alliance YMCA-John R. Mott House, 1963 Geneva (Box 163, Folder 2703)
  - JRM Centennial observances, 1965 (Box 163, Folder 2704)
  - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2705)
  - Greeting from Finnish organization, n.d. (Box OV1)
  - Lists of honors received by JRM of positions held by JRM (Box 163, Folder 2706)
  - Chronologies, 1888-1924 (Box 163, Folder 2707)
  - Personal finances of JRM, 1925-1938 (Box 163, Folder 2708)
  - Personal finances of JRM, 1939-1954, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 2708A)
  - "Date and Place Card File", 1888-1926 (Box 164, Folder 2709)
- Subject Files, Series VIII
  The material of this series is arranged alphabetically by topic
  A. Biography
  B. Related to specific countries or geographical areas
  C. Related to specific organizations
  D. Topical
  The material for each organization served by Mott is chronologically
  arranged under appropriate headings.
  - Biography
    - Acton, Lord (Box 165, Folder 2710)
    - Agassiz, Louis (Box 165, Folder 2711)
    - Aggrey, Dr. J.E.K. (Box 165, Folder 2712)
    - Aitchison, Charles U. (Box 165, Folder 2713)
    - Alexander the Great (Box 165, Folder 2714)
    - Anderson, Martin B. (Box 165, Folder 2715)
    - Andrews, C.F. (Box 165, Folder 2716)
    - Anthony, Susan B. (Box 165, Folder 2717)
    - Aristides (Box 165, Folder 2718)
    - Armstrong, Samuel Chapman (Box 165, Folder 2719)
    - Babcock, Maltbie Davenport (Box 165, Folder 2720)
    - Balch, Emily Greene (Box 165, Folder 2721)
    - Baldwin, Matthias W. (Box 165, Folder 2722)
    - Banerjea, Kali Charan (Box 165, Folder 2723)
    - Billings, Frederick and Julia (Box 165, Folder 2724)
    - Blaine, James G. (Box 165, Folder 2725)
    - Boies, Henry Martyn (Box 165, Folder 2726)
    - Bonar, Andrew A. (Box 165, Folder 2727)
    - Booth, Catherine (Box 165, Folder 2728)
    - Borden, William Whiting (Box 165, Folder 2729)
    - Botha, Louis (Box 165, Folder 2730)
    - Brainerd, David (Box 165, Folder 2731)
    - Brent, Charles Henry (Box 165, Folder 2732)
    - Bright, John (Box 165, Folder 2733)
    - Broadus, John Albert
    - Brockman, Fletcher S. (Box 165, Folder 2734)
    - Brooks, Phillips (Box 165, Folder 2735)
    - Brown, George and John A. (Box 165, Folder 2736)
    - Bryce, James (Box 165, Folder 2737)
    - Buchanan, George (Box 165, Folder 2738)
    - Bulgakoff, Sergius (Box 165, Folder 2739)
    - Burlingame, Anson (Box 165, Folder 2740)
    - Burns, Robert (Box 165, Folder 2741)
    - Butterfield, Kenyon L. (Box 165, Folder 2742)
    - Caesar (Box 165, Folder 2743)
    - Carter, Robert (Box 165, Folder 2744)
    - Cato, Marcus (Box 165, Folder 2745)
    - Cavour, Count (Camillo Benso) (Box 166, Folder 2746)
    - Chalmers, Doctor (Box 166, Folder 2747)
    - Churchill, Winston (Box 166, Folder 2748)
    - Cicero (Box 166, Folder 2749)
    - Cleveland, Grover (Box 166, Folder 2750)
    - Cochran, Joseph P. (Box 166, Folder 2751)
    - Crane, Charles R. (Box 166, Folder 2752)
    - Creighton, Bishop (Box 166, Folder 2753)
    - Cromwell, Oliver (Box 166, Folder 2754)
    - Curzon, Lord (Box 166, Folder 2755)
    - Dana, James Dwight (Box 166, Folder 2756)
    - Darwin, Charles (Box 166, Folder 2757)
    - Davidson, Randall Thomas (Box 166, Folder 2758)
    - Dawson, Sir William (Box 166, Folder 2759)
    - Demosthenes (Box 166, Folder 2760)
    - deVilliers, Lord (Box 166, Folder 2761)
    - Dods, Marcus (Box 166, Folder 2762)
    - Dollar, Robert (Box 166, Folder 2763)
    - Drummond, Henry (Box 166, Folder 2764)
    - Duff, Alexander (Box 166, Folder 2765)
    - Earle, A.B. (Box 166, Folder 2766)
    - Eddy, Sherwood (Box 166, Folder 2767)
    - Edward VII (Box 166, Folder 2768)
    - Edwards, Jonathan (Box 166, Folder 2769)
    - Elizabeth, Queen of Romania (Box 166, Folder 2770)
    - E linwood, Frank Field (Box 166, Folder 2771)
    - Finney, Charles Grandison (Box 166, Folder 2772)
    - Fisher, Geoffrey Francis (Box 166, Folder 2773)
    - Fletcher, John (Box 166, Folder 2774)
    - Foch, Ferdinand (Box 166, Folder 2775)
    - Ford, Henry (Box 166, Folder 2776)
    - Forman, John Newton (Box 166, Folder 2777)
    - Foster, Thomas D. (Box 166, Folder 2778)
    - Francis of Assisi (Box 166, Folder 2779)
    - Fraser, Andrew (Box 166, Folder 2780)
    - Frederick the Great (Box 166, Folder 2781)
    - Freeman, Edward (Box 166, Folder 2782)
    - Fry, Elizabeth (Box 166, Folder 2783)
    - Gandhi, Mahatma (author) (Box 167, Folder 2784)
    - Gandhi, Mahatma (subject) (Box 167, Folder 2785)
    - Gandhi, Mahatma (subject) (Box 167, Folder 2786)
    - Garbett, Cyril Forster (Box 167, Folder 2787)
    - Garfield, James J. (Box 167, Folder 2788)
    - George, Henry (Box 167, Folder 2789)
    - Gibbons, James (Box 167, Folder 2790)
    - Gladden, Washington (Box 167, Folder 2791)
    - Gladstone, William E. (Box 167, Folder 2792)
    - Glenn, John Mark (Box 167, Folder 2793)
    - Gordon, Adoniram Judson (Box 167, Folder 2794)
    - Gordon, Charles George (Chinese) (Box 167, Folder 2795)
    - Gordon, George A. (Box 167, Folder 2796)
    - Goreh, Father (Box 167, Folder 2797)
    - Gough, John B. (Box 167, Folder 2798)
    - Gould, Helen Miller (Box 167, Folder 2799)
    - Gould, Jay (Box 167, Folder 2800)
    - Grant,Ulysses S. (Box 167, Folder 2801)
    - Greene, Daniel C. (Box 167, Folder 2802)
    - Grotius, Hugo (Box 167, Folder 2803)
    - Gunsalus, Frank W. (Box 167, Folder 2804)
    - Hall, George A. (Box 167, Folder 2805)
    - Hall, Newman (Box 167, Folder 2806)
    - Hamilton, Alexander (Box 167, Folder 2807)
    - Hankey, Donald (Box 167, Folder 2808)
    - Harbison, Samuel Pollock (Box 167, Folder 2809)
    - Harper, James and Joseph (Box 167, Folder 2810)
    - Harriman, Edward (Box 167, Folder 2811)
    - Hart, Robert (Box 167, Folder 2812)
    - Haygood, Laura (Box 167, Folder 2813)
    - Heinz, Henry J. (Box 167, Folder 2814)
    - Hepburn, J.C. (Box 168, Folder 2815)
    - Hogg, Quintin (Box 168, Folder 2816)
    - Hopkins, Mark (Box 168, Folder 2817)
    - Howard, John (Box 168, Folder 2818)
    - Hughes, Hugh Price (Box 168, Folder 2819)
    - Huss, John (Box 168, Folder 2820)
    - Jackson, Arthur (Box 168, Folder 2821)
    - Jackson, Stonewall (Box 168, Folder 2822)
    - Jesup, Morris Ketchum (Box 168, Folder 2823)
    - Jones, Rufus (Box 168, Folder 2824)
    - Jowett, Benjamin (Box 168, Folder 2825)
    - Kagawa (Box 168, Folder 2826)
    - Keller, Helen (Box 168, Folder 2827)
    - Kitchener, Lord (Box 168, Folder 2828)
    - Knox, John (Box 168, Folder 2829)
    - Kuyper, Abraham (Box 168, Folder 2830)
    - Lang, Cosmo Gordon (Box 168, Folder 2831)
    - Larrabee, William (Box 168, Folder 2832)
    - LeConte, Joseph (Box 168, Folder 2833)
    - Lee, Robert E. (Box 168, Folder 2834)
    - Lincoln, Abraham and Nancy Hanks (Box 168, Folder 2835)
    - Lister, Lord (Box 168, Folder 2836)
    - Livingstone, David (Box 168, Folder 2837)
    - Low, Seth (Box 168, Folder 2838)
    - Lull, Ramon (Box 168, Folder 2839)
    - Luther, Martin (Box 168, Folder 2840)
    - McAll, Robert Whitaker (Box 168, Folder 2841)
    - McCheyne, Robert
    - MacKay, Alexander (Box 168, Folder 2842)
    - McKinley, William
    - MacNeil, John
    - Manning, Cardinal (Box 168, Folder 2843)
    - Marx, Karl
    - Masaryk, Tomas (Box 168, Folder 2844)
    - Mazzini, Giuseppe (Box 168, Folder 2845)
    - McCormick, Cyrus Hall and Nettie F. (Box 168, Folder 2846)